<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<metadata><Esri><CreaDate>20130411</CreaDate><CreaTime>11474300</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><SyncOnce>FALSE</SyncOnce><ArcGISProfile>ItemDescription</ArcGISProfile><DataProperties><itemProps><itemName Sync="TRUE">Metadata.txt</itemName><imsContentType Sync="TRUE">005</imsContentType></itemProps></DataProperties><SyncDate>20130411</SyncDate><SyncTime>11560000</SyncTime><ModDate>20130411</ModDate><ModTime>11560000</ModTime></Esri><dataIdInfo><idPurp>Forest Residues:  This category includes logging residues and other removable material left after carrying out silviculture operations and site conversions. Logging residue comprises unused portions of trees, cut or killed by logging and left in the woods. Other removable materials are the unutilized volume of trees cut or killed during logging operations. Source: USDA, Forest Service's Timber Product Output database, 2007.  Primary Mill Residues:  Primary mill residues include wood materials (coarse and fine) and bark generated at manufacturing plants (primary wood-using mills) when round wood products are processed into primary wood products, such as slabs, edgings, trimmings, sawdust, veneer clippings and cores, and pulp screenings. Source: USDA, Forest Service's Timber Product Output database, 2007.For more information on the data development, please refer to http://www.nrel.gov/docs/fy06osti/39181.pdf. Although, the document contains the methodology for the development of an older assessment, the information is applicable to this assessment as well. The difference is only in the data's time period. Data in dry tonnes.</idPurp><idCitation><resTitle>Forest and Primary Mill Residues</resTitle><presForm><PresFormCd value="001"></PresFormCd></presForm></idCitation><searchKeys><keyword>Biomass; United States; Forest and Primary Mill Residues; 2008</keyword></searchKeys><envirDesc Sync="TRUE">Microsoft Windows XP Version 5.1 (Build 2600) Service Pack 3; ESRI ArcGIS 10.0.0.2414</envirDesc><dataLang><languageCode value="en" country="US"></languageCode></dataLang><descKeys><thesaName uuidref="723f6998-058e-11dc-8314-0800200c9a66"></thesaName><keyword Sync="TRUE">002</keyword></descKeys></dataIdInfo><mdLang><languageCode value="en"></languageCode></mdLang><distInfo><distFormat><formatName Sync="TRUE">Text File</formatName></distFormat></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="007"></ScopeCd></mdHrLv><mdHrLvName Sync="TRUE">non-geographic dataset</mdHrLvName><mdDateSt Sync="TRUE">20130411</mdDateSt></metadata>